getbeamer.com 2019-04-17

# Beamer – Privacy policy

This **privacy policy** explains how we collect, use and disclose information about you when you use the services provided by Beamer (“we”, “us” or “our”) via [www.getbeamer.com](https://www.getbeamer.com/) and [app.getbeamer.com](https://app.getbeamer.com/) (the “Site”) (collectively, the “Service”).

Beamer operates **www.getbeamer.com**. It is Beamer’s policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites. Your privacy is very important to us. We do our best to not ask for personal information unless we truly need it and we do not share or store personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.

**Did you know Beamer is GDPR compliant?** We believe strongly in our user’s rights to security and privacy. If you are in the European Union or want to learn more on the subject [click here](https://www.getbeamer.com/blog/how-beamer-is-complying-with-gdpr/).

### Website Visitors

Like most website operators, Beamer collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Beamer’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Beamer’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Beamer may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Beamer also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users. Beamer only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below.

### Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information

Certain visitors to Beamer choose to interact with Beamer in ways that require Beamer to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Beamer gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up to provide a username and email address. Those who engage in transactions with Beamer are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions.

In each case, Beamer collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Beamer. Beamer does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

**Personal Data collected** | **Purpose**  
---|---  
Anonymized format IP address | User behaviour analysis  
Device screen resolution | User behaviour analysis  
Device type (unique device identifiers), operating system, and browser type | User behaviour analysis  
Geographic location (approximate) | User behaviour analysis  
Preferred language used to access Beamer | Improve user experience  
Mouse events (movement, location and clicks) | User behaviour analysis  
Keypresses | User behaviour analysis  
Referring url and domain | User behaviour analysis  
Pages visited | User behaviour analysis  
Date and time when website pages were visited | User behaviour analysis  
Random user ID | User behaviour analysis  
Full name (optional) | Improve user experience  
Email address (optional) | Improve user experience  
  
### Aggregated Statistics

Beamer may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Beamer may monitor the most liked and viewed entries. Beamer may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Beamer does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

### Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information

Beamer discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Beamer’s behalf or to provide services available at Beamer’s website, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Beamer’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them.

Beamer will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Beamer discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Beamer believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Beamer, third parties or the public at large.

If you are a registered user of a Beamer website and have supplied your email address, Beamer may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Beamer and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Beamer takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

### Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Beamer uses cookies to help Beamer identify and track visitors, their usage of Beamer website, and their website access preferences. Beamer visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Beamer’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Beamer’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

### Use of Third Party providers

We use a select number of trusted Third Party providers to help us provide Services to You. We only share information with the Third Party that is required for the service they are offering and contractually bind these providers to keep any information We share with them as confidential and to be used only for particular purposes. For example, amongst others, We have providers that process Our credit card transactions, support Our internal ticketing/support system, and manage Our marketing communications. Similarly, it may be necessary to share Your personal information or part of it, with Google Cloud which stores the information within their servers, solely related to the storage facilities. By using Beamer, You explicitly consent to, and authorize us to sub-contract in this manner.

### Business Transfers

If Beamer, or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Beamer goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur and that any acquirer of Beamer may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

### Promotional Communications

You may opt out of receiving promotional emails or text messages from Beamer by following the instructions in those emails or text messages. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account or our ongoing business relations.

### Data Processing Agreement

Prior to using Beamer our Data Processing Agreement should be requested and signed by the company or organization implementing Beamer (“Controller”). The Controller should send an email to legal@getbeamer.com requesting the Data Processing Agreement, fill out and return a signed copy. Beamer will return a signed copy within 10 days of receiving the Data Processing Agreement completed by the Controller.

### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this **Privacy Policy,** please contact us at info@getbeamer.com

### Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Beamer may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Beamer’s sole discretion. Beamer encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
